<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Beerapp</string>

    <string name="explore">Explore the Beers</string>
    <string name="favorites">My Favorites</string>
    <string name="about">This is an app developed by Christos Christidis, Odysseas Lomvardeas and Alexandros Sofoulakis
    as a university project. We do not own the rights to these images or the branded trademarks of the beers. Please drink responsibly. DISCLAIMER: ALl information
    and data has been gathered from Wikipedia within the Creative Commons license limitations without any intention of commercial use. </string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to BeerApp!</string>
    <string name="aboutButton">About</string>



    <string-array name="beerImageLinks">
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/6b/Real_Ale_2004-05-09_cropped.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4e/Earl_Grey_Pale_Ale_can_-_Andy_Mabbett.jpg/800px-Earl_Grey_Pale_Ale_can_-_Andy_Mabbett.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6c/Westmalle_Dubbel_7.jpg/800px-Westmalle_Dubbel_7.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/06/Timmermans_framboise.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/dd/Piwo_z_Grodziska_2.jpg/800px-Piwo_z_Grodziska_2.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c8/Geuze10.JPG/800px-Geuze10.JPG </item>
        <item> https://products0.imgix.drizly.com/ci-henrys-orange-soda-97acc8b94ab10a44.png </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5f/Ice_beer_%2820064322654%29.jpg/1280px-Ice_beer_%2820064322654%29.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8f/Brewdog-hardcore-ipa_%28cropped%29.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d9/Bitburger_Glass.JPG/1920px-Bitburger_Glass.JPG </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/30/Bieren_uit_de_streek_rond_brussel.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/70/Flickr_-_cyclonebill_-_%C3%98l_og_snaps.jpg/1280px-Flickr_-_cyclonebill_-_%C3%98l_og_snaps.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7e/CountryClubShiner.jpg/800px-CountryClubShiner.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6f/LiefmansOudbruin.jpg/1024px-LiefmansOudbruin.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/da/Pilsner_urquell_mug.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/70/Porter_Example_%28cropped%29.jpg/800px-Porter_Example_%28cropped%29.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/1b/Terrapin_Brewing_Co._Rye_Squared_Imperial_Pale_Ale.jpg/800px-Terrapin_Brewing_Co._Rye_Squared_Imperial_Pale_Ale.jpg</item>
        <item> https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saison#/media/File:Saison_Dupont.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f7/Norwegian_sour_beer.jpg/800px-Norwegian_sour_beer.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fe/Stadin_Panimo_Double_Oat_Malt_Stout.jpg/800px-Stadin_Panimo_Double_Oat_Malt_Stout.jpg</item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f0/2013_Augustiner_Weissbier_Munich_pub.jpg/800px-2013_Augustiner_Weissbier_Munich_pub.jpg </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shortDescriptions">

        <item>Ale is a type of beer brewed using a warm fermentation method, resulting in a sweet,
            full-bodied and fruity taste. Historically, the term referred to a drink brewed without hops.</item>
        <item> Beer made from bread instead of cereal grains </item>
        <item>  A strong version of a brown beer brewed in Westmalle Abbey in 1856, which is known to have been on sale to the public by June 1861 </item>
        <item> A Belgian lambic beer that is fermented using raspberries. It is one of
            many modern types of fruit beer that have been inspired by the more traditional kriek beer, which is made using sour cherries </item>
        <item> A historical style of beer from Poland that is typically made from oak-smoked wheat malt. </item>
        <item> Belgian beer made by blending young (1-year-old) and old (2- to 3-year-old) lambics, which is bottled for a second fermentation. </item>
        <item> A type of alcoholic beverage and craft beer that is manufactured in the style of a soft drink.  </item>
        <item> A beer that has undergone some degree of fractional freezing during production</item>
        <item> A hoppy beer style within the broader category of pale ale</item>
        <item> A  beer which has been brewed and conditioned at low temperature. </item>
        <item> A type of beer brewed in the Pajottenland region of Belgium southwest of Brussels and in Brussels itself since the 13th century.  </item>
        <item> A beer, usually a pale lager, that is reduced in alcohol content or in calories compared to regular beers </item>
        <item> A  beer with high alcohol content </item>
        <item> Also known as Flanders Brown, is a style of beer originating from the Flemish region of Belgium</item>
        <item>  A type of pale lager. It takes its name from the Bohemian city of Pilsen (Plzeň), where it was first produced in 1842 by Bavarian brewer Josef Groll.</item>
        <item> A style of beer that was developed in London, England in the early eighteenth century.[1] It was well-hopped and dark in appearance owing to the use of brown malt </item>
        <item> Rye beer refers to any beer in which rye (generally malted) is substituted for some portion of the barley. </item>
        <item> A pale ale that is highly carbonated, fruity, spicy, and often bottle conditioned </item>
        <item> Sour beer is beer which has an intentionally acidic, tart, or sour taste.
            Traditional sour beer styles include Belgian lambics, gueuze and Flanders red ale, and German gose </item>
        <item> Stout is a dark, top-fermented beer with a number of variations, including dry stout, oatmeal stout, milk stout, and imperial stout. </item>
        <item> Wheat beer is a top-fermented beer which is brewed with a large proportion of wheat relative to the amount of malted barley. </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="beerStyles">
        <item> Ale </item>
        <item> Bread Beer </item>
        <item> Dubbel </item>
        <item> Framboise </item>
        <item> Grodziskie </item>
        <item> Gueuze </item>
        <item> Hard Soda </item>
        <item> Ice Beer </item>
        <item> IPA </item>
        <item> Lager </item>
        <item> Lambic </item>
        <item> Light Beer </item>
        <item> Malt Liquor </item>
        <item> Oud Bruin </item>
        <item> Pilsner </item>
        <item> Porter </item>
        <item> Rye Beer </item>
        <item> Saison </item>
        <item> Sour Beer  </item>
        <item> Stout </item>
        <item> Wheat Beer </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="longDescriptions">
        <item> As with most beers, ale typically has a bittering agent to balance the malt and act as a preservative. Ale was originally bittered with gruit,
            a mixture of herbs or spices boiled in the wort before fermentation. Later, hops replaced gruit as the bittering agent. Ale was an important source
            of nutrition in the medieval world. It was one of three main sources of grains at the start of the fourteenth century in England, along with pottage
            and breads. Scholars believe grains accounted for around 80% of the calorie intake of agricultural workers and 75% for soldiers. Even nobles received
            around 65% of their calories from grains. Small beer, also known as table beer or mild beer, which was highly nutritious, contained just enough alcohol
            to act as a preservative, and provided hydration without intoxicating effects. Small beer would have been consumed daily by almost everyone,
            including children, in the medieval world, with higher-alcohol ales served for recreational purposes. The lower cost for proprietors combined with the
            lower taxes levied on small beer led to the selling of beer labeled "strong beer" that had actually been diluted with small beer. </item>

        <item> Beers made from bread include Sahti in Finland, Kvass in Russia and Ukraine, and Bouza in Egypt and Sudan.
            In several countries, 'Toast Ale' is made—in a range of styles—from surplus bread from the catering trade, as part of a campaign to reduce food waste.
            The recipe is open source. Inspired by this, Adnams brewed a range of three beers exclusively for Marks and Spencer in 2018,
            using leftover bread from the store's sandwich suppliers. All the waste bread was then used as animal feed. </item>

        <item> Westmalle's Dubbel was imitated by other breweries across the world, both Trappist and secular, leading to the emergence of a style. Dubbels are now understood to be a fairly strong
            (6–8% alcohol by volume) brown ale, with understated bitterness, fairly heavy body, and a pronounced fruitiness and cereal character.
            Dubbels are characteristically known for being dark brown in colour with a strong flavour of dark fruit including raisins, prunes, and dates.
            These flavours and colours are almost entirely resultant from the heavy addition of highly caramelized (or kilned) beet sugar, which
            ferments completely into alcohol, lightening the body of the finished beer and contributing to its dry finish. The caramelization of the beet sugar is
            also the major contributor of maillard flavors including chocolatey, caramel, and nutty tones that give the dubbel its wide gamut of flavour complexity.
            Because of the special strains of ale yeast used in their production, dubbels often carry a mild spice; coriander and black pepper are notable examples in traditional Belgian dubbels. </item>

        <item> Framboise is usually served in a small footed glass that resembles a champagne flute, only shorter. Most framboise beers are quite sweet, though the Cantillon Brewery produces a tart
            version called Rosé de Gambrinus that is based on the traditional kriek style. The Liefmans brewery uses oud bruin beer instead of lambic to make its framboise beer, resulting in a very different taste.
            There are other beers outside of Belgium, however, that can be considered "framboise."
            For example, the New Glarus Brewing Company in Wisconsin produces a beer called "Raspberry Tart" which they describe as a "Wisconsin Framboise Ale. </item>

        <item> The beer can be described as having a clear, light golden color, high carbonation, low alcohol content, low to moderate levels of hop bitterness, and a
            strong smoke flavor and aroma. The taste is light and crisp, with primary flavors coming from the smoked malt, the high mineral content of the water, and
            the strain of yeast used to ferment the beverage. The beer was nicknamed "Polish Champagne" because of its high carbonation levels, and because it was
            valued as a high-quality beverage to be used for special occasions. Grodziskie is brewed from wheat malt that has been dried by circulating oak smoke
            through the grains. The smokiness of the grain and the mineral profile of the water used to brew the beverage gives the style its characteristic flavor.
            Polish breweries historically used locally grown hops and one or two strains of brewer's yeast in its production. Before packaging, the beer is filtered
            to produce a bright, clear appearance. The beer is packaged before all of the fermentable sugars have been converted to alcohol by the yeast, earlier in
            the process than is typical in beers. Fermentation continues after packaging, and the carbon dioxide that is produced remains dissolved in the beer,
            resulting in a very high level of carbonation in the final product. </item>

        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
        <item>  </item>
    </string-array>


</resources>