<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Beerapp</string>

    <string name="explore">Explore the Beers</string>
    <string name="favorites">My Favorites</string>
    <string name="about">Strictly 18+.
        This is an app developed by Christos Christidis, Odysseas Lomvardeas and Alexandros Sofoulakis
    as a university project. We do not own the rights to these images or the branded trademarks of the beers. Please drink responsibly. Do not drink and drive.
        DISCLAIMER: ALl information and data has been gathered from Wikipedia within the Creative Commons license limitations without any intention of commercial use. </string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to BeerApp!</string>
    <string name="aboutButton">About</string>
    <string name="leftArrow" >Left Arrow </string>
    <string name="rightArrow" >Right Arrow </string>



    <string-array name="beerImageLinks">
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/15/Ale_glas_retuschiert.jpg/800px-Ale_glas_retuschiert.jpg</item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4e/Earl_Grey_Pale_Ale_can_-_Andy_Mabbett.jpg/800px-Earl_Grey_Pale_Ale_can_-_Andy_Mabbett.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6c/Westmalle_Dubbel_7.jpg/800px-Westmalle_Dubbel_7.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/06/Timmermans_framboise.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/dd/Piwo_z_Grodziska_2.jpg/800px-Piwo_z_Grodziska_2.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c8/Geuze10.JPG/800px-Geuze10.JPG </item>
        <item> https://products0.imgix.drizly.com/ci-henrys-orange-soda-97acc8b94ab10a44.png </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5f/Ice_beer_%2820064322654%29.jpg/1280px-Ice_beer_%2820064322654%29.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8f/Brewdog-hardcore-ipa_%28cropped%29.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d9/Bitburger_Glass.JPG/1920px-Bitburger_Glass.JPG </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/30/Bieren_uit_de_streek_rond_brussel.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/70/Flickr_-_cyclonebill_-_%C3%98l_og_snaps.jpg/1280px-Flickr_-_cyclonebill_-_%C3%98l_og_snaps.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7e/CountryClubShiner.jpg/800px-CountryClubShiner.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6f/LiefmansOudbruin.jpg/1024px-LiefmansOudbruin.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/da/Pilsner_urquell_mug.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/70/Porter_Example_%28cropped%29.jpg/800px-Porter_Example_%28cropped%29.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/1b/Terrapin_Brewing_Co._Rye_Squared_Imperial_Pale_Ale.jpg/800px-Terrapin_Brewing_Co._Rye_Squared_Imperial_Pale_Ale.jpg</item>
        <item> https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saison#/media/File:Saison_Dupont.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f7/Norwegian_sour_beer.jpg/800px-Norwegian_sour_beer.jpg </item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fe/Stadin_Panimo_Double_Oat_Malt_Stout.jpg/800px-Stadin_Panimo_Double_Oat_Malt_Stout.jpg</item>
        <item> https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f0/2013_Augustiner_Weissbier_Munich_pub.jpg/800px-2013_Augustiner_Weissbier_Munich_pub.jpg </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shortDescriptions">

        <item>Ale is a type of beer brewed using a warm fermentation method, resulting in a sweet,
            full-bodied and fruity taste. Historically, the term referred to a drink brewed without hops.</item>
        <item> Beer made from bread instead of cereal grains </item>
        <item>  A strong version of a brown beer brewed in Westmalle Abbey in 1856, which is known to have been on sale to the public by June 1861 </item>
        <item> A Belgian lambic beer that is fermented using raspberries. It is one of
            many modern types of fruit beer that have been inspired by the more traditional kriek beer, which is made using sour cherries </item>
        <item> A historical style of beer from Poland that is typically made from oak-smoked wheat malt. </item>
        <item> Belgian beer made by blending young (1-year-old) and old (2- to 3-year-old) lambics, which is bottled for a second fermentation. </item>
        <item> A type of alcoholic beverage and craft beer that is manufactured in the style of a soft drink.  </item>
        <item> A beer that has undergone some degree of fractional freezing during production</item>
        <item> A hoppy beer style within the broader category of pale ale</item>
        <item> A  beer which has been brewed and conditioned at low temperature. </item>
        <item> A type of beer brewed in the Pajottenland region of Belgium southwest of Brussels and in Brussels itself since the 13th century.  </item>
        <item> A beer, usually a pale lager, that is reduced in alcohol content or in calories compared to regular beers </item>
        <item> A  beer with high alcohol content </item>
        <item> Also known as Flanders Brown, is a style of beer originating from the Flemish region of Belgium</item>
        <item>  A type of pale lager. It takes its name from the Bohemian city of Pilsen (Plzeň), where it was first produced in 1842 by Bavarian brewer Josef Groll.</item>
        <item> A style of beer that was developed in London, England in the early eighteenth century. It was well-hopped and dark in appearance owing to the use of brown malt </item>
        <item> Rye beer refers to any beer in which rye (generally malted) is substituted for some portion of the barley. </item>
        <item> A pale ale that is highly carbonated, fruity, spicy, and often bottle conditioned </item>
        <item> Sour beer is beer which has an intentionally acidic, tart, or sour taste.
            Traditional sour beer styles include Belgian lambics, gueuze and Flanders red ale, and German gose </item>
        <item> Stout is a dark, top-fermented beer with a number of variations, including dry stout, oatmeal stout, milk stout, and imperial stout. </item>
        <item> Wheat beer is a top-fermented beer which is brewed with a large proportion of wheat relative to the amount of malted barley. </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="beerStyles">
        <item> Ale </item>
        <item> Bread Beer </item>
        <item> Dubbel </item>
        <item> Framboise </item>
        <item> Grodziskie </item>
        <item> Gueuze </item>
        <item> Hard Soda </item>
        <item> Ice Beer </item>
        <item> IPA </item>
        <item> Lager </item>
        <item> Lambic </item>
        <item> Light Beer </item>
        <item> Malt Liquor </item>
        <item> Oud Bruin </item>
        <item> Pilsner </item>
        <item> Porter </item>
        <item> Rye Beer </item>
        <item> Saison </item>
        <item> Sour Beer  </item>
        <item> Stout </item>
        <item> Wheat Beer </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="longDescriptions">
        <item> As with most beers, ale typically has a bittering agent to balance the malt and act as a preservative. Ale was originally bittered with gruit,
            a mixture of herbs or spices boiled in the wort before fermentation. Later, hops replaced gruit as the bittering agent. Ale was an important source
            of nutrition in the medieval world. It was one of three main sources of grains at the start of the fourteenth century in England, along with pottage
            and breads. Scholars believe grains accounted for around 80% of the calorie intake of agricultural workers and 75% for soldiers. Even nobles received
            around 65% of their calories from grains. Small beer, also known as table beer or mild beer, which was highly nutritious, contained just enough alcohol
            to act as a preservative, and provided hydration without intoxicating effects. Small beer would have been consumed daily by almost everyone,
            including children, in the medieval world, with higher-alcohol ales served for recreational purposes. The lower cost for proprietors combined with the
            lower taxes levied on small beer led to the selling of beer labeled "strong beer" that had actually been diluted with small beer. </item>

        <item> Beers made from bread include Sahti in Finland, Kvass in Russia and Ukraine, and Bouza in Egypt and Sudan.
            In several countries, \'Toast Ale\' is made—in a range of styles—from surplus bread from the catering trade, as part of a campaign to reduce food waste.
            The recipe is open source. Inspired by this, Adnams brewed a range of three beers exclusively for Marks and Spencer in 2018,
            using leftover bread from the store\'s sandwich suppliers. All the waste bread was then used as animal feed. </item>

        <item> Westmalle\'s Dubbel was imitated by other breweries across the world, both Trappist and secular, leading to the emergence of a style. Dubbels are now understood to be a fairly strong
            (6–8% alcohol by volume) brown ale, with understated bitterness, fairly heavy body, and a pronounced fruitiness and cereal character.
            Dubbels are characteristically known for being dark brown in colour with a strong flavour of dark fruit including raisins, prunes, and dates.
            These flavours and colours are almost entirely resultant from the heavy addition of highly caramelized (or kilned) beet sugar, which
            ferments completely into alcohol, lightening the body of the finished beer and contributing to its dry finish. The caramelization of the beet sugar is
            also the major contributor of maillard flavors including chocolatey, caramel, and nutty tones that give the dubbel its wide gamut of flavour complexity.
            Because of the special strains of ale yeast used in their production, dubbels often carry a mild spice; coriander and black pepper are notable examples in traditional Belgian dubbels. </item>

        <item> Framboise is usually served in a small footed glass that resembles a champagne flute, only shorter. Most framboise beers are quite sweet, though the Cantillon Brewery produces a tart
            version called Rosé de Gambrinus that is based on the traditional kriek style. The Liefmans brewery uses oud bruin beer instead of lambic to make its framboise beer, resulting in a very different taste.
            There are other beers outside of Belgium, however, that can be considered "framboise."
            For example, the New Glarus Brewing Company in Wisconsin produces a beer called "Raspberry Tart" which they describe as a "Wisconsin Framboise Ale. </item>

        <item> The beer can be described as having a clear, light golden color, high carbonation, low alcohol content, low to moderate levels of hop bitterness, and a
            strong smoke flavor and aroma. The taste is light and crisp, with primary flavors coming from the smoked malt, the high mineral content of the water, and
            the strain of yeast used to ferment the beverage. The beer was nicknamed "Polish Champagne" because of its high carbonation levels, and because it was
            valued as a high-quality beverage to be used for special occasions. Grodziskie is brewed from wheat malt that has been dried by circulating oak smoke
            through the grains. The smokiness of the grain and the mineral profile of the water used to brew the beverage gives the style its characteristic flavor.
            Polish breweries historically used locally grown hops and one or two strains of brewer\'s yeast in its production. Before packaging, the beer is filtered
            to produce a bright, clear appearance. The beer is packaged before all of the fermentable sugars have been converted to alcohol by the yeast, earlier in
            the process than is typical in beers. Fermentation continues after packaging, and the carbon dioxide that is produced remains dissolved in the beer,
            resulting in a very high level of carbonation in the final product. </item>

        <item> Because the young lambics are not fully fermented, the blended beer contains fermentable sugars, which allow a second fermentation to occur. Since
            gueuze is made by blending lambics, it tastes different from traditional ale and lager style beers. Because aged hops are used to produce these lambics,
            the beer has little to none of the traditional hop flavor and aroma that can be found in most other styles of beer. Furthermore, the wild yeasts that are
            specific to lambic-style beers give gueuze a dry, cider-like, musty, sour, acetic acid, lactic acid taste. Many describe the taste as sour and "barnyard-like".
            Because of its carbonation, gueuze is sometimes called "Brussels Champagne". In modern times, some brewers have added sweeteners such as aspartame to their
            gueuzes to sweeten them, trying to make the beer more appealing to a wider audience. The original, unsweetened version is often referred to as "Oude Gueuze"
            ("Old Gueuze") and became more popular in the early 2000s. Tim Webb, a British writer on Belgian and other beers, comments on the correct use of the term
            "\'Oude gueuze\' or \'oude geuze\', now legally defined and referring to a drink made by blending two or more 100% lambic beer."</item>

        <item> Hard soda, also referred to as flavored beer, adult soda, fermented soda, mature soda and alcohol soda, is a type of alcoholic beverage and craft beer
            that is manufactured in the style of a soft drink. It has gained recent prominence in the United States after the success of the Not Your Father\'s
            Root Beer brand manufactured by Small Town Brewery. As of late May 2016, at least 39 hard soda brands exist in the United States. Such beverages
            are usually found in the market as a fusion between fruit juice (e.g. lemon juice) and beer.</item>

        <item> These brands generally have higher alcohol content than typical beer and generally have a low price relative to their alcohol content. The process of
            "icing" beer involves lowering the temperature of a batch of beer until ice crystals form. Since ethanol has a much lower freezing point (-114 °C; -173.2 °F)
            than water (0 °C; 32 °F), when the ice is removed, the alcohol concentration of the beer increases. The process is known as fractional freezing or freeze
            distillation.</item>

        <item> The pale ales of the early 18th century were lightly hopped and quite different from today\'s pale ales. By the mid-18th century, pale ale was mostly
            brewed with coke-fired malt, which produced less smoking and roasting of barley in the malting process, and hence produced a paler beer. One such
            variety of beer was October beer, a pale well-hopped brew popular among the landed gentry, who brewed it domestically; once brewed it was intended to cellar
            two years. Among the first brewers known to export beer to India was George Hodgson\'s Bow Brewery, on the Middlesex-Essex border. Its beers became
            popular among East India Company traders\' provisions in the late 18th century: for being two miles up the Lea from the East India Docks; and Hodgson\'s
            liberal credit line of 18 months. Ships exported this beer to India, among them his October beer, which benefited exceptionally from conditions of the voyage
            and was apparently highly regarded among its consumers in India. The brewery came into the control of Hodgson\'s son early in the next century, but his
            business practices alienated customers. During the same period, several Burton breweries lost their European export market in Europe,
            Scandinavia and Russia when the Napoleonic blockade was imposed, and Burton brewers were seeking a new export market for their beer. </item>

        <item> Lager beer uses a process of cool fermentation, followed by maturation in cold storage. The German word "Lager" means storeroom or warehouse.
            The yeast generally used with lager brewing is Saccharomyces pastorianus. It is a close relative of the Saccharomyces cerevisiae yeast used for
            warm fermented ales. While prohibited by the German Reinheitsgebot tradition, lagers in some countries often feature large proportions of adjuncts,
            usually rice or maize. Adjuncts entered United States brewing as a means of thinning out the body of beers, balancing the large quantities of protein
            introduced by six-row barley. Adjuncts are often used now in beermaking to introduce a large quantity of sugar, and thereby increase ABV, at a lower
            price than a formulation using an all-malt grain bill. There are however cases in which adjunct usage actually increases the cost of manufacture.
            It is possible to use lager yeast in a warm fermentation process, such as with American steam beer; while German Altbier and Kölsch are brewed with
            Saccharomyces cerevisiae top-fermenting yeast at a warm temperature, but with a cold-storage finishing stage, and classified as obergäriges lagerbier
            (top-fermented lager beer). </item>

        <item> Lambic is generally brewed from a grist containing approximately 60–70% barley malt and 30–40% unmalted wheat. The wort is cooled overnight in a shallow,
            flat metal pan (generally copper or stainless steel) called a coolship where it is left exposed to the open air so more than 120 different types of
            microorganisms may inoculate the wort. This cooling process requires night-time temperatures between -8C (18F) and 8C (46F). While this cooling
            method of open air exposure is a critical feature of the style, the key yeasts and bacteria that perform the fermentation reside within the breweries\'
            timber fermenting vessels. Over eighty microorganisms have been identified in lambic beer, the most significant being Saccharomyces cerevisiae,
            Saccharomyces pastorianus and Brettanomyces bruxellensis. The process is generally only possible between October and May as in the summer months
            there are too many unfavourable organisms in the air that could spoil the beer. In Brussels dialect, lambic produced after this traditional brewing
            season is referred to as bezomerd, meaning that it has had "too much summer". Climate change is further shortening this limited brewing window: in the
            early 1900s, lambic brewers enjoyed roughly 165 days a year in the ideal temperature range, whereas by 2018 that number has shrunk to 140. </item>

        <item> The first use of the term in marketing was in the 1940s when the Coors Brewing Company sold Coors Light, for a short period before World War II,
            relaunching it more successfully in 1978 as a 4.2% abv pale lager. In 1967, the Rheingold Brewery marketed a 4.2% pale lager, Gablinger\'s Diet Beer,
            developed by American biochemist Joseph Owades, as a beer for people dieting. It was not successful, and the recipe was given to a Chicago brewery,
            Meister Brau, who sold it as Meister Brau Lite. That brewery was acquired by the Miller Brewing Company in 1972, who relaunched the beer as Miller Lite.
            Light beers may be chosen by beer drinkers who wish to manage their alcohol consumption or their calorie intake; however, they are sometimes criticised
            for being less flavourful than full-strength beers, or for tasting or actually being watered down.</item>

        <item> Malt liquor is typically straw to pale amber. While typical beer is made primarily from barley, water, and hops, malt liquors tend to make much
            greater use of inexpensive adjuncts such as corn, rice, or dextrose. Use of these adjuncts, along with the addition of special enzymes, results in
            a higher percentage of alcohol than an average beer. Higher alcohol versions, sometimes called "high-gravity" or just "HG", may contain high levels of
            fusel alcohols, which gives off solvent- or fuel-like aromas and flavors. Owing to inconsistencies in American alcoholic beverage regulations, which
            can vary from state to state, the term "malt liquor" lacks a stable definition. In some states, malt liquor refers to any alcoholic beverage made by
            fermenting grain and water; in these states a non-alcoholic beer may also be called a non-alcoholic or non-intoxicating malt liquor. In some states,
            products labeled "beer" must fall below a certain alcohol content, and beers that exceed the mark must be labeled as "malt liquor". While ordinary
            beers in the United States average around 5% alcohol by volume, malt liquors typically range from 6% up to 9% alcohol by volume. </item>

        <item> The Dutch name refers to the long aging process, up to a year. It undergoes a secondary fermentation, which takes several weeks to a month, and is
            followed by bottle aging for several more months. The extended aging allows residual yeast and bacteria to develop a sour flavor characteristic for this style.
            Usually, cultured yeast and bacterias are used, as stainless steel equipment
            does not harbor wild organisms as wood does. </item>

        <item> Czech Pilsner beers are pale golden in color with considerable but balanced malt and hop character. They are seductively complex, refreshing and easy to drink.
            Classic Pilsners are made with light-colored Pilsner malt, Saaz and Hallertau noble hops, and a bottom fermenting Pilsner yeast. They have an alcohol by volume
            level of 4.2-5.8 percent and generally are quite sessionable. </item>

        <item> The name originated from its popularity with street and river porters. The popularity of porter was significant, and it became the first beer style
            to be brewed across the world, and production had commenced in Ireland, North America, Sweden and Russia by the end of the eighteenth century. The history
            of stout and porter are intertwined. The name "stout", used for a dark beer, is believed to have come about because strong porters were marketed under
            such names as "extra porter", "double porter", and "stout porter". The term stout porter would later be shortened to just stout. For example, Guinness
            Extra Stout was originally called "Extra Superior Porter" and was not given the name "Extra Stout" until 1840. Today, however, there are not many
            distinctions between stouts and porters; the terms are used by different breweries almost interchangeably to describe dark beers, and the two styles have
            more in common than in distinction </item>

        <item> Rye beers are considered specialty beers that are brewed with unusual fermentables such as rice, corn, or wheat. One example of this is Roggenbier,
            which is a specialty beer produced with up to 60% rye malt. The style originated in Bavaria, in southern Germany, and is brewed with the same type of
            yeast as a German Hefeweizen, resulting in a similar light, dry, spicy taste. In the United States, another style of rye beer is being developed by
            homebrewers and microbreweries. In some examples, the hops presence is pushed to the point where they resemble American India pale ales (IPAs).
            This style is often called a Rye IPA, or just a "Rye-P-A", a take-off of the abbreviation for an India Pale Ale: "IPA". </item>

        <item> It was historically brewed with low alcohol levels, but modern productions of the style have moderate to high levels of alcohol. Along with several
            other varieties, it is generally classified as a farmhouse ale. The type of malt determines the color of the saison, and although most saisons are of a
            cloudy golden color as result of the grist being mostly pale or pilsner malt, the use of darker malts results in some saisons being reddish-amber. Some
            recipes also use wheat. Spices such as orange zest, coriander, and ginger may be used. Some spice character may come through due to the production of esters
            during fermentation at warm temperatures. Modern examples brewed in the US tend to copy the yeast used by the Dupont Brewery, which ferments better at warmer
            temperatures like 29 to 35 °C (84 to 95 °F) than the standard 18 to 24 °C (64 to 75 °F) fermenting temperature used by other Belgian ales. </item>

        <item> Unlike modern brewing, which is done in a sanitary environment to guard against the intrusion of wild yeast, historically the starter used from one batch
            to another usually contained some wild yeast and bacteria. Sour beers are made by intentionally allowing wild yeast strains or bacteria into the brew,
            traditionally through the barrels or during the cooling of the wort in a coolship open to the outside air. The most common microbes used to intentionally
            sour beer are bacteria Lactobacillus and Pediococcus, while Brettanomyces can also add some acidity. Another method for achieving a tart flavor is adding
            fruit, which directly contributes organic acids such as citric acid. Additionally, acid can be directly added to beer or added by the use of excessive
            amounts of acidulated malt. Depending on the process employed, the uncertainty involved in using wild yeast may cause the beer to take months to ferment and
            potentially years to mature. However, modern methods allow sour beer to be created within a typical timeframe for ales, several days </item>

        <item> The first known use of the word stout for beer was in a document dated 1677 found in the Egerton Manuscripts, the sense being that a "stout beer" was a
            strong beer, not a dark beer. The name porter was first used in 1721 to describe a dark brown beer that had been made with roasted malts. Because of
            the huge popularity of porters, brewers made them in a variety of strengths. The stronger beers, typically 7% or 8% alcohol by volume (ABV), were called
            "stout porters", so the history and development of stout and porter are intertwined, and the term stout has become firmly associated with dark beer,
            rather than just strong beer. </item>

        <item> The two main varieties are German Weizenbier and Belgian witbier; other types include Lambic (made with wild yeast), Berliner Weisse (a cloudy, sour beer),
            and Gose (a sour, salty beer). Weißbier (German – "white beer") uses at least 50% wheat to barley malt to make a light coloured top-fermenting beer.
            Witbier (Dutch – "white beer") uses flavorings such as coriander and orange peel. Belgian white beers are often made with raw unmalted wheat. German Weißbier
            and Belgian witbier are termed "white beers" because "wheat" has the same etymological root as "white" in most West Germanic languages (including English).
            Other wheat beer styles, such as Berliner Weiße, Gose, and Lambic, are made with a significant proportion of wheat. </item>

    </string-array>




</resources>